magnoliamarket.com 2019-04-05

# Privacy Policy – Magnolia Market Helpdesk

At Magnolia, we respect our guests and understand that you are concerned about privacy. Therefore, Magnolia Market, LLC and its affiliates (collectively, “Magnolia”) have posted this Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) to let you know what kind of information we collect, how it is handled, and with whom it may be shared.

This Policy may change as we continue to develop our websites, mobile applications and online services or programs (collectively “websites”), so we encourage you to refer to this Policy on an ongoing basis, so that you understand our current Policy.

If you have any questions or concerns, please don't hesitate to contact us at shop@magnolia.com.

\----

**SECTION 1 – WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT**

We collect various types of information depending on how you use our websites, such as:

  * When you purchase something or make a donation from one of our websites, we collect certain personal information, such as your name, address, phone number, and email address, in order to process your purchase.       
  * When you send us a message, we collect your email address so that we can respond to you.
  * When you create an account with us, we collect personal information such as your name, address, and email address in order to expedite any future purchases.
  * When you register and/or participate in any event, program, contest, surveys or other promotion that we may offer from time to time (collectively, “Promotions”), we may collect certain contact information from you.
  * When you begin or complete the application process for employment by Magnolia Personnel Group, LLC, we collect personal information such as your name, address, and phone number in order to process your application.
  * When you access or use Magnolia pages or accounts on any third-party social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter or Instagram (“Social Media Pages”);
  * When you comment on our blog or sign up to receive news and special offers from us, we may use your email address in order to communicate with you about Magnolia products, services, or events we think may be of interest to you (as permitted by law). 
  * When you browse our websites, we may also collect certain “non-personal information,” which by itself, cannot be used to identify or contact you. This includes demographic information (such as your age, gender, income, education, zip code, etc.), technical information (such as your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address, device screen resolution, device type, operating system, mouse movements, location and clicks, keypresses and the type of browser you are using), and information you provide us while using our websites (such as the terms you enter in the search function of our websites). This information helps us evaluate consumer trends and usage related to our websites, and allows us to improve our website content and offerings accordingly.
  * In addition to the above-described information, we and our third-party service providers may collect additional information when you utilize any of our mobile applications, including the type of mobile device you use, the temporary or persistent unique device identifiers (sometimes called UDID), the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browser you use, and information about the way you use our mobile applications. 

We will retain your personal information as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or not prohibited by law.

**SECTION 2 – YOUR CONSENT**

In many circumstances, we will not collect or process your personal information without your consent.  We will ask for your express consent where required or where we find it appropriate. If you choose not to consent, please do not use our website, products, or services, and do not provide us with any personal information.  You may withdraw your consent at any time by emailing us at shop@magnolia.com or mailing us at: Magnolia Market 7503 Bosque Boulevard, Suite 201, Waco, Texas 76712 United States.

**SECTION 3 – HOW WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION**

**Affiliated Parties**

We may share your personal information with certain entities that control us, are controlled by us, or are under common control with Magnolia Market, LLC (our "Affiliates"), so that they and we can offer you products and services that may be of interest to you. We require that our Affiliates agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.  These Affiliates include the following entities, all of which are located in the United States:

  * Magnolia Flour, LLC, d/b/a Silos Baking Co.
  * Magnolia FTT, LLC d/b/a Magnolia Table
  * Magnolia Waco Properties, LLC d/b/a Magnolia Homes
  * Magnolia Vacation Rentals, LLC
  * Square MB, LLC d/b/a Magnolia Realty
  * Magnolia Personnel Group, LLC
  * Magnolia Brands, LLC
  * Magnolia Foundation

**Online Advertising and Third Parties**

We work with certain third parties for advertising or promotional purposes, including to: conduct special events; serve advertisements across the Internet; track and categorize your activity and interests over time on our websites and mobile applications, and on third-party websites and mobile applications; and to identify the different devices you use to access websites and mobile applications.  We may share your information with these third parties as described in this Policy, and these third parties may collect information from you independently as described in their privacy policies. The information that these companies collect or that we share may be used to customize or personalize the advertisements that are displayed to you.  

We may share personal information with the third parties we work with for advertising purposes; however, we generally do not share personal information about you with third parties for third-party marketing or advertising purposes. We may also share aggregate information, such as demographic information, and our statistical analyses, to third parties in our discretion.  This aggregate information does not include your personal information. 

We may also share your personal information with third-party providers that perform services for us.  For example, our web store is hosted by Shopify Inc.  We share your personal information with service providers such as Shopify in order to provide our website and products and services to you. Any credit card or bank account information you provide our websites will not be stored on our servers, and is instead passed directly to the third-party provider.  When we work with a third-party provider, we require that these parties agree to process your personal information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Policy and applicable laws. 

Please remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located in a different jurisdiction than either you or us. If you choose to use our websites, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdictions in which our third-party providers or their facilities are located.

**Other Disclosures**

Additionally, we may disclose your personal information and other related information in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also collect and share personal information in order to investigate or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, violations of our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law or by government and regulatory authorities.

**Links and Social Network Posting Tools**

Our websites may provide links to other third-party websites that are outside our control and not covered by this policy. For example, our websites provide social network posting and sharing buttons that allow you to post links to our content on your social network pages. When you click on these buttons or other links on our websites, the third party operating the linked site may be collecting information about your browser, device, and online activity through its own tracking technologies and subject to its own separate privacy policy, which may differ from ours. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy policies.

**Information You Post to Our Websites**

Keep in mind that any information that you choose to post to our websites, including product reviews and blog comments, can be seen, collected, and used by anyone who visits our websites. We are not responsible for unauthorized third-party uses of such information.

**Collection and Use of Personal Information of Magnolia Personnel Group, LLC Employment Applicants**

If you complete an application for employment with Magnolia Personnel Group, LLC, or request information regarding such opportunities, we collect personal information that you provide in connection with your request for information and/or to evaluate your application for employment with Magnolia Personnel Group, LLC.  We may also collect personal information about you from third parties to supplement, update or verify your information, and/or to process your application for consideration as a Magnolia Personnel Group, LLC employee.  For example, our online employment application form is provided by Bamboo HR LLC, and we recommend that you review their privacy policy to understand how this third party handles your personal information. Applicable law may require that you authorize a third party to share your personal information with us before we can acquire it. 

**SECTION 4 – HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We take reasonable physical, technical, and organizational measures to protect the personal information collected on our websites. Of course, no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure. As we deem appropriate, we use security measures consistent with industry standards. However, we cannot guarantee the security of our databases, nor can we guarantee that information you provide us won’t be intercepted during transmission over the Internet.

**SECTION 5 – COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES**

When you visit or interact with our websites, we or our third-party providers may use cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies in order to operate our websites and services, to improve our performance, or to give you extra functionalities, all with the goal of providing a better experience for you.

Third parties that have content embedded on our website (such as buttons, widgets, and other embedded features or content) may set cookies on your browser or obtain information about the fact that you visited our websites from a certain IP address. Our third-party providers may also collect personal information as described in the section above. We do not authorize third parties to collect any other personal information from our websites unless you provide it to them directly.

**What Are Cookies and How to Disable Them**

A “cookie” is a small piece of information send to a visitor’s computer or other Internet-connected devices to uniquely identify the visitor’s browser or to store information or settings in the browser. It holds information a site may need to interact with you and personalize your experience. Our websites use both session cookies and persistent cookies.

Session cookies enable you to move from page to page and to use features on our websites while your browser remains open. For example, session cookies allow you to add products to your shopping cart and carry the contents of your cart to checkout.

Persistent cookies last from visit to visit. For example, persistent cookies may be used to recognize you as a previous user to provide a more personalized experience. They are stored in your computer, device, or browser until you choose to delete them.

The majority of web browsers accept cookies and similar files, but you can usually change the browser settings to prevent this. However, if you do so, some functionality of this website may be lost. Please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) for more information about cookies and how to disable them.

**Do Not Track**

Our websites currently do not respond to Do Not Track signals in browsers. 

**SECTION 6 – CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

It is our policy not to knowingly collect personal information from individuals under the age of 13. If you are a parent/guardian and you suspect that your child may have submitted personal information to us, please send us an [email](mailto:shop@magnoliamarket.com). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will strive to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

If you are under 18 years of age and live in California, you have the right to request removal of content posted by you on our websites. Upon receipt of a fully completed removal request, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to remove content posted by you from our websites. Any such request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of your posted content. For example, your posted content may continue to appear on our websites if it has been reposted by others. Additionally, while we may remove the content you posted from our websites, it may continue to be stored on our servers (although it will not be visible to other users of our websites). You must complete the removal request form accurately and in its entirety in order for the request to be processed.

**How to Provide a California Minor Removal Request**

If you are a user under the age of 18 and reside in California, and you wish for your published content to be removed from our websites, please provide our Agent listed below with the following information in a written notice:

  1. Confirmation that you are currently a legal resident of the state of California;
  2. Confirmation that you are under the age of 18 by providing your birthday;
  3. A description of the exact content that you are seeking to have removed (please provide a URL if possible);
  4. Your full name; and
  5. Your email address.

Our designated Agent for California Minor Removal Requests can be reached as follows:

Service Provider:  Magnolia Market, LLC

Name of Agent of Request: Stone Crandall

By mail: 7503 Bosque Blvd., Suite 203, Waco, Texas 76712 United States

By email: shop@magnolia.com (please add “California Minor Removal Request” to the subject line)

**SECTION 7 – YOUR CALIFORNIA RIGHTS**

Residents of the State of California have the right to request a list of all third parties to which we have disclosed certain information during the preceding year for the third parties' direct marketing purposes.  However, it is our policy to neither disclose personal information, nor to sell such information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes without your consent.

**SECTION 8 – CHANGES TO THIS POLICY**

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. This Policy was last updated May 24, 2018.

If our business undergoes a fundamental change such as, for example, a sale, merger, or transfer of all or a portion of our business or assets, we may disclose your personal information to the other parties in the transaction so that we may continue to provide products and services to you.

**SECTION 9 – ACCESS AND CORRECTIONS**

You may contact us at any time at shop@magnolia.com to (1) see what personal information we have about you, if any, (2) change or correct any personal information we have about you, 3) have us delete any personal information we have about you, or 4) express any complaints or concerns you have about our use of your personal information. It is not technologically possible to change or delete each and every instance of the information we hold on you from our systems, and data may remain in non-erasable or aggregate form. We may retain data in our backup or temporary systems. We may also retain some information for longer periods as required or permitted by law, contract, or auditing requirements.

**SECTION 10  – INFORMATION RECEIVED FROM NON-U.S. RESIDENTS **

If you are located outside the United States, please note that you may be transferring your personal information to a country that does not have the same data protection laws as your home country.  For personal information received from the European Union, European Economic Area, or Switzerland, Magnolia is committed to handling your personal information in accordance with this Policy and the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield (or the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield, as the case may be), as administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce. If there is any conflict between the terms of this Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield frameworks, and to view Magnolia’s certification, please visit: [https://www.privacyshield.gov/list](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

Magnolia’s accountability for personal information that it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Magnolia remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third parties engaged by Magnolia process the personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Magnolia proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

As further explained in the "Questions and Contact Information" section below, we encourage you to contact us should you have a Privacy Shield-related (or general privacy-related) complaint.

**SECTION 11 – QUESTIONS AND CONTACT INFORMATION**

We welcome your feedback and questions about this Policy. If for any reason you wish to contact us, please send us an [email](mailto:shop@magnoliamarket.com).

Any complaints will be resolved internally in accordance with our complaints procedures. If you live in the European Union, European Economic Area, or Switzerland and efforts to resolve the matter internally are unsatisfactory, the complaint may be submitted to the American Arbitration Association ([http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html](http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html)), which has been selected as the independent recourse mechanism to resolve complaints and disputes relating to treatment of data originating in the European Union, European Economic Area, or Switzerland under this Policy. We are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC).
